<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Curosity is the most powerful thing you own</title>
    <link>http://hellodk.in/</link>
    <description>A beautiful narrative written over an elegant publishing platform. The story begins here...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 17:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>RabbitMQ - Detecting Dead TCP Connections with Heartbeats</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//detecting-dead-tcp-connections</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In some types of network failure, packet loss can mean that disrupted TCP connections take a moderately long time (about 11 minutes with default configuration on Linux, for example) to be detected by the operating system. AMQP 0-9-1 offers a heartbeat feature to ensure that the application layer promptly finds out about disrupted connections (and also completely unresponsive peers). Heartbeats also defend against certain network equipment which may terminate &quot;idle&quot; TCP connections. See Heartbeats for details.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 17:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2017-04-24T17:48:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Quick Reference - A Quick reminder about HTTP</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//http_quick_reference</link>
      <description>In this tutorial we will cover the basics of an HTTP request and see how it works.
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;u&gt;HTTP Transaction Model:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HTTP protocol is transaction-driven. This means that each request will lead
to one and only one response. Traditionally, a TCP connection is established
from the client to the server, a request is sent by the client on the
connection, the server responds and the connection is closed. A new request
will involve a new connection :&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2017-04-20T18:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HA Proxy for Beginners</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//ha_proxy_for_beginners</link>
      <description>

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2017-04-20T18:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RethinkDb Installation on Ubuntu-14.04</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//rethinkdb_installation_ubuntu14</link>
      <description>Let's get some hands on rethinkdb today and find it out yourself. &lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
So what is rethinkdb?
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
Rethinkdb is an open-source, scalable JSON database built from the ground up for the realtime web.
&lt;/br&gt;RethinkDB inverts the traditional database architecture by exposing an exciting new access model – instead of polling for changes, the developer can tell RethinkDB to continuously push updated query results to applications in realtime. RethinkDB’s realtime push architecture dramatically reduces the time and effort necessary to build scalable realtime apps. RethinkDB also offers a flexible query language, intuitive operations and monitoring APIs, and is easy to setup and learn. Just like any other database solution, rethinkdb ships as a client-server component model. The installation process for both the server and the client are illustrated below:

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 15:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-09-21T15:48:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UNIX Time-Sharing System</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//unix_time_sharing_system</link>
      <description>                              Drafted By

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 13:48:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-02-01T13:48:37+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markdown cheat-sheets</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//mark_down_cheatsheet</link>
      <description>Source : https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet

[arbitrary case-insensitive reference text]: https://www.mozilla.org
[1]: http://slashdot.org
[link text itself]: http://www.reddit.com
[logo]: https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/raw/master/src/common/images/icon48.png &quot;Logo Title Text 2&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 13:48:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-02-01T13:48:37+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Cassandra</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//getting_familiar_with_cassandra</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Growth of Big Data - Big Data is one of the key forces driving the growth and popularity of NoSQL for business. The almost limitless array of data collection technologies ranging from simple online actions to point of sale systems to GPS tools to smartphones and tablets to sophisticated sensors – and many more – act as force multipliers for data growth.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 15:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-01-28T15:48:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 interesting cloud predictions for 2016</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//5_interesting_cloud_predictions_2016</link>
      <description>1. It's time for IOT-

</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 15:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-01-28T15:48:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//about</link>
      <description>Too often we under-estimate the power of a touch, a smile, a kind word, a listening ear, an honest compliment, or the smallest act of caring, all of which have the potential to turn a life around. 
The idea behind writing this blog/website is to conect to people and share my experiences with them.

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 15:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2015-12-28T15:48:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Highly Available Distributed Messaging System</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//Creating-a-Highly-Available-Distributed-Messaging-Queue-Cluster-with-RabbitMQ-3.5.6</link>
      <description>Creating a Highly Available Distributed Messaging Queue Cluster with RabbitMQ-3.5.6
What is rabbitmq?

</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 15:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2015-12-19T15:48:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Git-Flow</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//understanding_git_flow</link>
      <description>Understanding Git Flow for(ubuntu-14.04):

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2015-11-09T00:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Going Agntless with Ansible</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//going_agentless_with_ansible</link>
      <description>While looking for a light yet powerful Configuration Management tool, I was going through some of the various available tools, and came across Ansible. After having a quick look at the features, something which caught my attention: &quot;Ansible is agent-less&quot;, hence I decided to give it a try. Having used Ansible for some around more than 8+ months configuration management, I personally feel...Ansible is awesome!!
So what is Ansible? Well, it is a configuration management tool, and it empowers you to configure/orchestrate multiple systems at great ease, saving a lot of downtime and resources.
So how does it does that? The answer lies with ssh keys based agent forwarding. Ansible uses ssh for logging to the remote system, and can execute package installation, shell commands, install/update package management systems, clone git and anything under the sun you need for configuration management.
So why don't you try your hands on Ansible and experience it's awesomeness....all you need to do is to install it on your host system.

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 15:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2015-04-06T15:48:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Camera Basics</title>
      <link>http://hellodk.in//camera-basics</link>
      <description>A basic tutorial on handling a DSLR for beginners.

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 1963 15:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>1963-08-28T15:48:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <dc:date>2017-04-24T17:48:00+05:30</dc:date>
  </channel>
</rss>